<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Boomi Training Notes</title>
    <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Boomi Training Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 14:52:20 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mapping</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 14:52:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/mapping/</guid>
      <description>Mapping shows how elements in the source profile correspond with those in the destination profile.
Mapping Methods Manual - you click and drag source profile elements to the corresponding destination profile element Boomi Suggest Wizard - Boomi makes mapping suggestions based on thousands of mappings loggged by the Boomi community Mapping Considerations Setting a Default Value AtomSphere assigns a default value to a dest. profile element when no value exists in source Need to create a defualt value if destination profile requires a field value that is not contained in the source profile Ways that maps use default values: Source profiles Element is null Elemet is blank Destination profiles Element is null Elemet is blank When you map a source element to a destination element with a default value the default value is not used </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Profiles</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/working-with-profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 14:02:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/working-with-profiles/</guid>
      <description> Describe layout or format of documents read into or sent out of a processes Provide information like field names, column positions, deliminters, data types, min/max lens Not shapes Contain data elements of a specific document/doc type Ways to create profiles: Manual - use data elements tab to add elements and attributes to an XML profile Import a File or Schema - import connection information Import the connection operation Profiles describe the document layout in or out of AtomSphere Profiles is saved to the component library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining Documents and Understanding Flow</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/defining-documents-and-understanding-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 13:45:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/defining-documents-and-understanding-flow/</guid>
      <description>Documents A document is a set of data that flows through the Boomi process. It can be a single record, a group of records, or and entire file. Boomi supports the following document types: XML Json Flat File Database You can only use these documents or profile types in Atmosphere. Source files and destination files must be one of these types Documents flow together as group, but each shape processes them individually </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running a Process in Test Mode</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/running-a-process-in-test-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 13:44:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/running-a-process-in-test-mode/</guid>
      <description>Test mode allows you to quickly test processes from build page without deploying the process to an Atom.
Provides immediate feedback during development Saves time and effort Test mode supports connector retrieval of 100 max document count or 10 MB total data size View logs and connection data after running test in test results window </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Shapes</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/working-with-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 09:07:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/working-with-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Shapes Steps linked together to form the business logic for a process Start shape is automatically added to a new processes Start shape cannot be removed There are 4 start shape types: Connector - gets data into the process using an application or technology connectors Trading partner - gets data into process for a specific trading partner and handles common EDI doc standarts like X12 or EDIFACT Data passthrough - gets data into process from a parent or another external source No data - process does not receive data from a source, but a single, empty document goes through the process flow Display name - if not entered, name of the selected shape appears on the shape Process Structure and Design Connector shape get data into or send data out of the process Connectors contain all information needed to connect to a data source or applicication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Environments</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 14:49:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-environments/</guid>
      <description>An envrionment is a workspace created by users for testing or production. An unlimited number of environments can be created.
It is a boomi recommendation to create an environment for Test and Production.
A runtime engine powers the program while it is running.
Atom Cloud is the runtime engine used in this training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Atom Clouds</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-atom-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 14:28:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-atom-clouds/</guid>
      <description>Atom Cloud Highly scalable, highly available execution environment. Supports large number of users. Connects to publicly accessible endpoints (only public). Boomi allows for easily adding clouds. Boomi uses regional-based clouds because it allows boomi to easily add clouds and makes sure
you always have a reliable and efficient process. Setting up the Atom and Test Atom Clounds Manage &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Atom Management &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; New</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 13:05:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m learning Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
