<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Boomi Training Notes</title>
    <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Boomi Training Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 08:24:11 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tracking New Customers</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/associate-integration-developer/tracking-new-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 08:24:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/associate-integration-developer/tracking-new-customers/</guid>
      <description>Profile - allows you to statically or dynamically define Read statements against a table or stored proceedure output. Link Element - an optional field that specifies the common database field in a record group to batch documents, usually the primary key. Batch count - defines an interval for the grouping behaviour. Max rows - limits the maximum number of frows returned in a single read. Salesforce Write Actions Create - creates new records in SF object defined in Create operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Different Connector Types</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/associate-integration-developer/understanding-different-connector-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 09:43:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/associate-integration-developer/understanding-different-connector-types/</guid>
      <description>Connectors are the main component that contain all the information needed to connect to a data source or application.
Why Use Connectors? Simplifies application support: Automatically updates to new versions Protects data access using different authentication types Automatically discovers the recently supported objects in the application API Supports advanced options to fine-tune behaviour Highly configurable Allows configuration, based on use case Advanced options allow for additional specification Built-in data manipulation Automatically pages through large data sets and retrieves the entire data set from the API Optimizes data transfer and efficiency by splitting large files into smaller chunks Supports batches to improve efficiency and performance Real-time support Provides listener support Provides real-time data validation and integration, including communication with trading partners Connector Types: Application - targeted at one specific application Technology - implement a specific protocol Event-driving - a hybrid of application and technology used in event or message-driven scenarios Custom - You can develop, deploy, and publish custom connectors by leveraging the Boomi Connector API using the Connector SDK and its companion SDK Javadocs Configuring a Salesfroce Read Connector The Salesforce read connector retrieves information from a Salesforce account</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/associate-integration-developer/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 08:34:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/associate-integration-developer/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Objectives Build, test, and troubleshoot intermediate-level integration processes Explain the Development Life Cycle Manage and Schedule Processes Describe the different property types Incorporate basic administration tasks Analyze how documents flow through a process and how to control them When developing a new integration you should organize processes and components into folder. Folders allows you to configure and save unique processes that contain workflow and processing rules for your business scenario. Should also store all of your connections in one location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Undeploying</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-undeploying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 15:39:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-undeploying/</guid>
      <description>Undeploying is when you remove a packaged component from the list of active deployments.
Reasons to Undeploy: Processes no longer needed - When you have a process that no longer needs to run a deployed environment, you can undeploy it Regain licenses - when you undeploy a process, you will regain the connection licenses After undeploying, the process still exists as a packaged component </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Process Reporting</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-process-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 15:29:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-process-reporting/</guid>
      <description>Process Reporting is useful because it allows you to search for information about process executions and the documents associated with them.
Uses Shows executed processes - by default, Process Reporting displays all deployed processes ran in the account within the past hour Manually execute a process - manually execute an integration process from Process Reporting by selecting an Atom and the process Filters process executions - process Manager filters executions by type, atom, time, and status Process reporting page: Execute button - let&amp;rsquo;s you manually execute a deployed process Auto refresh - if on, will refresh every minute Time frame - by default, processes run in the account over the past hour are displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 14:52:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/mapping/</guid>
      <description>Mapping shows how elements in the source profile correspond with those in the destination profile.
Mapping Methods Manual - you click and drag source profile elements to the corresponding destination profile element Boomi Suggest Wizard - Boomi makes mapping suggestions based on thousands of mappings loggged by the Boomi community Mapping Considerations Setting a Default Value AtomSphere assigns a default value to a dest. profile element when no value exists in source Need to create a defualt value if destination profile requires a field value that is not contained in the source profile Ways that maps use default values: Source profiles Element is null Elemet is blank Destination profiles Element is null Elemet is blank When you map a source element to a destination element with a default value the default value is not used </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Profiles</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/working-with-profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 14:02:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/working-with-profiles/</guid>
      <description> Describe layout or format of documents read into or sent out of a processes Provide information like field names, column positions, deliminters, data types, min/max lens Not shapes Contain data elements of a specific document/doc type Ways to create profiles: Manual - use data elements tab to add elements and attributes to an XML profile Import a File or Schema - import connection information Import the connection operation Profiles describe the document layout in or out of AtomSphere Profiles is saved to the component library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining Documents and Understanding Flow</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/defining-documents-and-understanding-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 13:45:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/defining-documents-and-understanding-flow/</guid>
      <description>Documents A document is a set of data that flows through the Boomi process. It can be a single record, a group of records, or and entire file. Boomi supports the following document types: XML Json Flat File Database You can only use these documents or profile types in Atmosphere. Source files and destination files must be one of these types Documents flow together as group, but each shape processes them individually </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running a Process in Test Mode</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/running-a-process-in-test-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 13:44:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/running-a-process-in-test-mode/</guid>
      <description>Test mode allows you to quickly test processes from build page without deploying the process to an Atom.
Provides immediate feedback during development Saves time and effort Test mode supports connector retrieval of 100 max document count or 10 MB total data size View logs and connection data after running test in test results window </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Shapes</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/working-with-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 09:07:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/working-with-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Shapes Steps linked together to form the business logic for a process Start shape is automatically added to a new processes Start shape cannot be removed There are 4 start shape types: Connector - gets data into the process using an application or technology connectors Trading partner - gets data into process for a specific trading partner and handles common EDI doc standarts like X12 or EDIFACT Data passthrough - gets data into process from a parent or another external source No data - process does not receive data from a source, but a single, empty document goes through the process flow Display name - if not entered, name of the selected shape appears on the shape Process Structure and Design Connector shape get data into or send data out of the process Connectors contain all information needed to connect to a data source or applicication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Environments</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 14:49:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-environments/</guid>
      <description>An envrionment is a workspace created by users for testing or production. An unlimited number of environments can be created.
It is a boomi recommendation to create an environment for Test and Production.
A runtime engine powers the program while it is running.
Atom Cloud is the runtime engine used in this training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Atom Clouds</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-atom-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 14:28:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/integration-essentials/understanding-atom-clouds/</guid>
      <description>Atom Cloud Highly scalable, highly available execution environment. Supports large number of users. Connects to publicly accessible endpoints (only public). Boomi allows for easily adding clouds. Boomi uses regional-based clouds because it allows boomi to easily add clouds and makes sure
you always have a reliable and efficient process. Setting up the Atom and Test Atom Clounds Manage &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Atom Management &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; New</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 13:05:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acatejr.github.io/boomi/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m learning Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
